你是对的  Android会将你的数据保存到文件系统中
As you might expect, Android stores your persistent data in the file system.
为了便于开发者的工作  Android在文件系统之上
To simplify what app developers need to write, Android provides
提供了几种结构化的存储选项
several structured storage options on top of the file system.
我们来详细讨论一下SharedPreferences和SQLite数据库
For Sunshine, we'll leverage both Shared Preferences and an SQLite Database.
下面让我们看一下
Let's look at both of these options.
我们之前存储用户邮编的SharedPreferences类
The Shared Preferences class, which we are already using to store our user
提供了一种存储和查询基础数据类型
zip code in units, provides a general framework that allows you to save and
键值对的通用框架
retrieve persistent key value pairs of primitive data types,
这里的基础数据类型包括布尔型  整型  长整型和字符串等
such as Booleans, floats, ins, longs and strings.
不过有些时候像SharedPreferences这样简单的键值对框架
There are times when a simple key value pair framework like Shared Preferences
无法提供足够的灵活性
doesn't provide enough flexibility.
幸运地是  Android还有SQLite数据库
Fortunately, Android also has SQLite.
SQLite数据库是一种轻量级的关系型数据库
SQLite implements a light weight relational database.
我们通过写查询方法  其它的方法
We interact with SQLite databases by writing queries and
或者SQL语句与SQLite数据库进行交互
statements and SQLite's variant of the structured query language or SQL.
在数据库中存储数据比使用SharedPreferences
Storing something in a a database is more complicated than using
要更加复杂
Shared Preferences.
那为什么还要使用数据库呢
So why would we ever choose this option?
毕竟  Android支持原始文件存储
After all, Android supports both raw files and
可以作为替代
shared preferences as alternatives.
好吧  这和你无法从地板上的一大堆衣服中快速地
Well, for the same reason that it's inefficient to find things if you
找到你想要的衣服的道理是一样的
throw your clothes in a pile on the floor.
在SQLite数据库中存储数据可以帮助你更简单地组织和查询数据
Storing things in an SQLite Database helps you organize and find data easily.
这多亏了索引和表
Thanks to the power of indexing and tables.
让我们看看究竟是怎么回事
Let's see what this looks like.
这是天气数据库中的一张表
Here is an SQLite Database table from our weather database.
注意我们没有展示所有的属性
Note not all fields are represented.
第一天的所有数据在第一行
All of the data for the first day is in the first row.
第二天的所有数据在第二行  以此类推
The data for the second day is in the second row and so on.
如果用键值对的话
With key valued pairs,
是很难组织这样的一行数据的
it would be difficult to associate a row of data this way.
随着后面对Android中数据库的继续学习
As you continue through this section on database storage and Android.
我们将会对SQLite数据库和关系型数据库有一些基本的理解
We're going to expect some basic understanding of SQLite and
包括创建  查找  更新  删除  插入
relational databases, including what a create, select,
这些操作的意思
update, delete and insert operation is.
我们将帮助你写这些操作的代码
We'll help you write these operations.
不过如果你从来没使用过SQLite或者需要复习一下
But if you are new to SQLite or need a refresher,
去SQLite教程看看  链接在下面的帮助指南中
head over to the tutorial linked in the instructor notes below.
一旦我们在应用中创建好了数据库  并运行在设备上
Once we have a database up and running on our device for our app.
使用SQL语句获取我们想要的信息是很简单的
Getting the information we need using SQL is easy.
我们可以对这个数据库进行查询操作  比如这里的SELECT语句
We can perform queries against this database, such as this SELECT statement
它会返回特定日期的天气数据
here, which returns the weather on the specified date.
在天气详情页面我们可能会需要这样的数据
Similar to what we would want to do for the detail view.
我们还可以使用稍微复杂一些的查询来返回一个时间段的天气信息
We can use this slightly more complex query to return a range of dates,
我们在天气预报列表页面应该会需要这样的数据
which is similar to what we'd do on the main forecast list view.
重申一遍  如果你对任何一点不熟悉  你可以
Once again, if any of this was unfamiliar, please consider working
查看SQLite教程  帮助指南中有链接
through the SQLite tutorial link in the instructor notes.
就算没有问题  你也可以学到一些东西
And even if isn't unfamiliar, you might just learn something.
好的
Okay.
这里有一个更加复杂一些的SQL查询语句
Here's a slightly more complicated SQL query.
从帮助指南中看看有没有
See the instructor notes for
你可以使用到的东西来帮助你解析这个SQL语句
some resources that you can use to help parse the SQL statement.
看看第一个  max是一天中最高温的那一栏
One note, max is the name of the column that stores the high temperature for
的属性名称
the day.